# John Weathers

703-915-8135 • weathers.johnb@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/john-weathers1 • github.com/john-weathers • johnweathers.dev

### **SUMMARY**

Computer science student with hands-on experience (2 years) in full stack development and object-oriented programming, using multiple languages. I am making a career transition after discovering an untapped passion and aptitude for programming. I believe I can show, through my prior experience, transferrable skills, and references, that I already have a strong track record of being a positive contributor to organizations as a full-time professional and would make an excellent team member.

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.S. Computer Science**Oregon State University, Corvallis, OR

4.0 GPA

**B.A. Communication**2014
George Mason University, Fairfax, VA
3.9 GPA

**TECHNICAL SKILLS** 

Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python, SQL, Bash

Front-End: HTML, CSS, React

Tools, Databases, and OS: Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Git, GitHub, Windows, MacOS

#### **RELEVANT PROJECTS**

# FixerApp (full stack web application), Personal Project

Summer 2023

- Built front end/back end, some technologies used include JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, Node/Express, MongoDB
- Front end includes modern use of React components, hooks, context, client-side routing, etc.
- Responsive design, app is mobile/tablet/desktop friendly
- Best-practice token-based authentication using JSON Web Tokens
- Integration with APIs for added features such as maps/geocoding/navigation and enhanced data fetching/caching
- Real-time updates using WebSockets and MongoDB change streams

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Pawthereum, Remote: Core Team Member

Oct 2021 – Apr 2024

- Strategized on and developed content for a community of multiple thousand people, ultimately helping the project achieve around \$500,000 in donations to animal shelters
- Worked with other decision makers, including the lead developer, to create a multi-year roadmap for future products

## United States Air Force, Vandenberg AFB, CA: Paralegal

Feb 2019 – Sep 2020

- Managed large office projects for the leadership team, including overhauling multiple processes relating to, for
  example, yearly inspections, forms for legal actions, and customer service processes, that led to
  streamlined/automated operations, reducing man-hours by several per week
- Researched legal issues, mainly regarding Air Force Instructions, providing analysis to supervising attorney
- Received 5/5 score on annual review, won best civilian of the quarter for the squadron

## Rogers, Sheffield and Campbell, LLP, Santa Barbara, CA: Paralegal

Feb 2017 - Oct 2018

- Led large-scale projects involving thousands of documents, solving multiple issues through attention to detail and
  organization, one example being a discovery issue that could have caused severe problems for the firm/client in a highstakes multi-million-dollar case
- Prepared and filed complex multi-volume legal briefs with the courts, never missing a deadline even when tasked same-day or sometimes with only several hours of notice
- Researched applicable California laws (e.g., civil litigation, trusts), providing analysis to supervising attorney